<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Vitamins &amp; Minerals Cheatsheet</string>

    <string name="carrot_credits">Image by Felix Mendoza from Pixabay</string>

    <string name="arrow_down">Arrow down</string>
    <string name="arrow_up">Arrow up</string>

    <string name="carrot_description">Carrot illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_a_name">Vitamin A</string>
    <string name="vitamin_a_scientific_names">Retinol, Retinal, Retinoic acid, Carotenoids</string>
    <string name="vitamin_a_benefits">Keeps your eyes healthy.\nMaintains healthy skin.\nHelps your body fight infections.\nHelps with growth and reproduction.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_a_sources">orange, yellow or green coloured fruits and vegetables\ngreen leafy vegetables\nmargarine\ndairy products — milk and cheese\nliver\nmeat\nfish and fish oil</string>
    <string name="vitamin_a_description"><![CDATA[Vitamin A is a fat-soluble vitamin that is stored in the liver.\nThere are two types of vitamin A that are found in the diet.\n-> Preformed vitamin A is found in animal products such as meat, fish, poultry, and dairy foods.\n-> Precursors to vitamin A, also known as provitamin A, are found in plant-based foods such as fruits and vegetables. The most common type of provitamin A is beta-carotene.\nVitamin A is also available in dietary supplements. It most often comes in the form of retinyl acetate or retinyl palmitate (preformed vitamin A), beta-carotene (provitamin A) or a combination of preformed and provitamin A.]]></string>

    <string name="seeds_description">Seeds illustration - AI generated</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b1_name">Vitamin B1</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b1_scientific_name">Thiamine</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b1_description">Thiamin(also spelled Thiamine) helps the body\'s cells change carbohydrates into energy. The main role of carbohydrates is to provide energy for the body, especially the brain and nervous system.\nThiamin also plays a role in muscle contraction and conduction of nerve signals.\nThiamin is essential for the metabolism of pyruvate, which is an important molecule in several chemical reactions in the body.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b1_benefits">Helps your body break down and release energy from food.\nKeeps your nervous system healthy.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b1_sources">Enriched, fortified, and whole grain products such as bread, cereals, rice, pasta, and flour\nWheat germ\nBeef steak and pork\nTrout and bluefin tuna\nEgg\nLegumes and peas\nNuts and seeds</string>

    <string name="dairy_description">Diary products illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b2_name">Vitamin B2</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b2_description">Riboflavin is a type of B vitamin. It is water-soluble, which means it is not stored in the body. Water-soluble vitamins dissolve in water. Leftover amounts of the vitamin leave the body through the fluid body waste. The body keeps a small reserve of these vitamins. They have to be taken on a regular basis to maintain the reserve.\nRiboflavin (vitamin B2) works with the other B vitamins. It is important for body growth. It helps in red blood cell production. It also aids in the release of energy from proteins.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b2_scientific_name">Riboflavin</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b2_sources">Dairy products\nEggs\nGreen leafy vegetables\nLean meats\nOrgan meats, such as liver and kidneys\nLegumes\nMilk\nNuts</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b2_benefits">Keeps your skin, eyes and nervous system healthy.\nHelps your body release energy from food.</string>

    <string name="mushroom_description">Red mushrooms</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b3_name">Vitamin B3</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b3_scientific_name">Niacin</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b3_description">Niacin is a type of B vitamin. It is water-soluble, which means it is not stored in the body. Water-soluble vitamins dissolve in water. Leftover amounts of the vitamin leave the body through the fluid body waste. The body keeps a small reserve of these vitamins. They have to be taken on a regular basis to maintain the reserve.\nNiacin helps the digestive system, skin, and nerves to function. It is also important for changing food to energy.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b3_benefits">Helps your body release energy from food.\nKeeps your nervous system and skin healthy.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b3_sources">Milk\nEggs\nEnriched breads and cereals\nRice\nFish\nLean meats\nLegumes\nPeanuts\nPoultry</string>

    <string name="avocado_description">Smiley avocado illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b5_name">Vitamin B5</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b5_scientific_name">Pantothenic acid</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b5_description">Pantothenic acid (vitamin B5) is essential for the metabolism of food. It also plays a role in the production of hormones and cholesterol. Pantothenic acid is also a water-soluble vitamin.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b5_benefits">Helps your body release energy from food.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b5_sources">Animal proteins\nAvocado\nBroccoli, kale, and other vegetables in the cabbage family\nEggs\nLegumes and lentils\nMilk\nMushrooms\nOrgan meats\nPoultry\nWhite and sweet potatoes\nWhole-grain cereals\nYeast</string>

    <string name="banana_description">Smiley banana illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b6_name">Vitamin B6</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b6_scientific_name">Pyridoxine</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b6_description">Vitamin B6 is a water-soluble vitamin. \nLack of vitamin B6 in the body is uncommon. It can occur in people with kidney failure, liver disease, or alcohol dependence.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b6_benefits">Make antibodies. Antibodies are needed to fight many viruses, infections, and other diseases.\nMaintain normal nerve function.\nMakes hemoglobin. Hemoglobin carries oxygen in the red blood cells to the tissues. A vitamin B6 deficiency can cause a form of anemia.\nBreaks down proteins. The more protein you eat, the more vitamin B6 you need.\nKeeps blood sugar (glucose) in normal ranges.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b6_sources">Tuna and salmon\nBanana\nLegumes (dried beans)\nBeef and pork\nNuts\nPoultry\nWhole grains and fortified cereals\nChickpeas</string>

    <string name="egg_description">Cracked egg illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b7_name">Vitamin B7</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b7_scientific_name">Biotin</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b7_description">Biotin (B7) is needed for energy metabolism, fat synthesis, amino acid metabolism and glycogen synthesis. High biotin intake can contribute to raised blood cholesterol levels.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b7_benefits">Help your nervous system function.\nHelps your body make fatty acids.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b7_sources">Cereal\nChocolate\nEgg yolk\nLegumes\nMilk\nNuts\nOrgan meats (liver, kidney)\nPork\nYeast</string>

    <string name="broccoli_description">Broccoli illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b9_name">Vitamin B9</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b9_scientific_name">Folate, Folic Acid</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b9_description">Folic acid and folate are both terms for a type of B vitamin (vitamin B9).\nFolate is a B vitamin that occurs naturally in foods such as green leafy vegetables, citrus fruit, and beans.\nFolic acid is man-made (synthetic) folate. It is found in supplements and added to fortified foods.\nThe terms folic acid and folate are often used interchangeably.\nVitamin B9 is also water-soluble.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b9_benefits">Helps tissues grow and cells work\nWorks with vitamin B12 and vitamin C to help the body break down, use, and create new proteins\nHelps form red blood cells (helps prevent anemia)\nHelps produce DNA, the building block of the human body, which carries genetic information</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b9_sources">fortified breads and cereals\nliver\nlegumes — chickpeas and kidney beans\ngreen leafy vegetables\npeas\nbroccoli\nbrussels sprouts\nasparagus</string>

    <string name="meat_description">Meat</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b12_name">Vitamin B12</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b12_scientific_name">Cobalamin, Cyanocobalamin</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b12_description">Vitamin B12, like the other B vitamins, is important for protein metabolism. It helps in the formation of red blood cells and in the maintenance of the nervous system. It is also a water-soluble vitamin.\n</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b12_benefits">Helps make red blood cells and keeps your nervous system healthy.\nHelps release energy from food.\nHelps your body to use folate.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_b12_sources">meat\nfish\neggs\nmilk\ncheese\nsome fortified cereals and fortified plant-based milks</string>

    <string name="lemons_description">Lemons with their leaf illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_c_name">Vitamin C</string>
    <string name="vitamin_c_scientific_name">Ascorbic acid</string>
    <string name="vitamin_c_description">Vitamin C is a water-soluble vitamin. It is needed for normal growth and development.\nVitamin C is one of many antioxidants. Antioxidants are nutrients that block some of the damage caused by free radicals.\nFree radicals are made when your body breaks down food or when you are exposed to tobacco smoke or radiation.\nThe buildup of free radicals over time is largely responsible for the aging process.\nFree radicals may play a role in cancer, heart disease, and conditions like arthritis.\nThe body is not able to make vitamin C on its own. It does not store vitamin C. It is therefore important to include plenty of vitamin C-containing foods in your daily diet.\nAll fruits and vegetables contain some amount of vitamin C.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_c_benefits">Antioxidant.\nKeeps your skin, bones, blood vessels and connective tissue healthy.\nHelps with wound healing.\nBoosts your immune system.\nHelps your body absorb iron.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_c_sources">citrus fruits\nkiwi fruit\nstrawberries\ntomatoes\ncabbage\ncauliflower\nbrussels sprouts\ncapsicum\npotatoes</string>

    <string name="sun_description">Smiling sun illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_d_name">Vitamin D</string>
    <string name="vitamin_d_scientific_name">Calciferol, Ergocalciferol, Cholecalciferol</string>
    <string name="vitamin_d_description">Vitamin D is a fat-soluble vitamin. Fat-soluble vitamins are stored in the body\'s fatty tissue and liver.\nVitamin D comes in 2 forms:\nVitamin D2 (ergocalciferol): comes from plant sources. \nVitamin D3 (cholecalciferol) is made in your skin when you are exposed to sunlight. It\'s also found in some animal foods and supplements.\nVitamin D helps the body absorb calcium. Calcium is a mineral that you must have for normal bone formation.\n\nIf you do not consume enough calcium in your diet, or if your body does not absorb enough calcium due to low vitamin D, bone production and bone tissues may suffer.\n\nVitamin D deficiency can lead to weakened bones (osteoporosis in adults or rickets in children).</string>
    <string name="vitamin_d_benefits">Needed to use calcium.\nImportant for healthy bones, immune system, skin, muscles and brain.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_d_sources">vitamin D forms in the skin when it is exposed to the sun\nsalmon, mackerel, herring and sardines\negg yolks\nfortified milk and margarine</string>

    <string name="sunflowers_description">Sunflowers illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_e_name">Vitamin E</string>
    <string name="vitamin_e_scientific_name">Tocopherol, Alpha-tocopherol</string>
    <string name="vitamin_e_description">"Vitamin E is a fat-soluble vitamin (dissolves in fat) that is found in several forms. Alpha tocopherol is the form used by your body.\nThe main role of vitamin E is to act as an antioxidant. Some antioxidants protect your cells against free-radicals (unpaired electrons). The best way to get the daily requirement of vitamin E is by eating food sources. "</string>
    <string name="vitamin_e_benefits">It is an antioxidant. This means it protects body tissue from damage caused by substances called free radicals. Free radicals can harm cells, tissues, and organs. They are believed to play a role in certain conditions related to aging.\nIt helps keep the immune system strong against viruses and bacteria.\nIt helps form red blood cells and widen blood vessels to keep blood from clotting inside them.\nIt helps the body use vitamin K.\nCells also use vitamin E to interact with each other. It helps them carry out many important functions.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_e_sources">Vegetable oils (such as wheat germ, sunflower, safflower, corn, and soybean oils)\nNuts (such as almonds, peanuts, and hazelnuts/filberts)\nSeeds (such as sunflower seeds)\nGreen leafy vegetables (such as spinach and broccoli)\nFortified breakfast cereals, fruit juices, margarine, and spreads.</string>

    <string name="kale_description">Kale illustration</string>
    <string name="vitamin_k_name">Vitamin K</string>
    <string name="vitamin_k_scientific_name">Phylloquinone, Menaquinones, Menadione </string>
    <string name="vitamin_k_description">Vitamin K is a fat-soluble vitamin, which is known as the clotting vitamin.\nThe body needs vitamin K to make certain proteins in the liver that cause blood to clot. These proteins are called clotting factors.  Without vitamin K, the liver could not produce clotting factors II, VII, IX, and X, and blood would not clot. Some studies suggest that vitamin K helps maintain strong bones in older adults.</string>
    <string name="vitamin_k_benefits">healthy bones\nblood clotting and wound healing\nprevents a serious bleeding condition called haemorrhagic disease of the newborn (HDN), in newborns</string>
    <string name="vitamin_k_sources">Green leafy vegetables, such as kale, spinach, turnip greens, collards, Swiss chard, mustard greens, parsley, romaine, and green leaf lettuce\nVegetables such as Brussels sprouts, broccoli, cauliflower, and cabbage\nFish, liver, meat, eggs, and cereals (contain smaller amounts)</string>

    <string name="cheese_description">Cheese illustration</string>
    <string name="calcium_name">Calcium</string>
    <string name="calcium_symbol">Ca</string>
    <string name="calcium_description">Calcium is a mineral that is vital for the healthy functioning of your body. It is especially important for building and maintaining healthy bones throughout your life. Your bones contain 99% of your body’s calcium.\nCalcium is important for strong bones, as well as for the healthy functioning of nerves, muscles and heart. Most people get enough calcium from their diet, although some people may need a supplement.\n\nYou need calcium to build and maintain healthy bones. Calcium combines with other minerals, such as phosphate, to give your bones structure and strength. Calcium also circulates in your blood to be used by your heart, muscles and nerves.\nTo absorb calcium, your body needs vitamin D. Even if you have plenty of calcium in your diet, if you don’t get enough vitamin D, you will have trouble absorbing calcium and keeping your bones healthy.\nThe best way to get enough calcium is to make sure you include high-calcium foods in your diet such as dairy foods. Dairy foods include milk, yoghurt and cheese.</string>
    <string name="calcium_benefits">builds bones\nmuscle and nerve function\nblood clotting</string>
    <string name="calcium_sources">milk\ncheese\nyoghurt\ngreen leafy vegetables\nfish where you eat the bones\nlegumes\nfortified breakfast cereals</string>

    <string name="salt_shaker_description">Illustrated salt shaker with salt label written</string>
    <string name="iodine_name">Iodine</string>
    <string name="iodine_symbol">I</string>
    <string name="iodine_description">Iodine is essential to make thyroid hormones. These hormones control your metabolic rate (the rate your body uses energy when it is resting). They also help your brain and body grow and develop.</string>
    <string name="iodine_benefits">thyroid gland function\nnormal growth</string>
    <string name="iodine_sources">seafood\nseaweed\nbread\niodised table salt and foods made with this type of salt</string>

    <string name="beans_description">Different colored kidney beans - AI generated</string>
    <string name="iron_name">Iron</string>
    <string name="iron_symbol">Fe</string>
    <string name="iron_description">Iron is a nutrient that comes from your diet. It\'s needed for many functions in your body, with one of the most important being to prevent anaemia. Iron is needed to make haemoglobin, a molecule found in your red blood cells. Haemoglobin moves oxygen through your body.\nWhile your body can store iron, it can\'t make iron. The only way to get iron is by consuming (eating) it.\nThere are 2 types of iron in food:\n\n1-haem iron — this is easily absorbed by the body\n2-non-haem iron — this is harder for your body to absorb\n\nHaem iron can be found in:\nmeat — beef, lamb, pork, and kangaroo\npoultry — chicken, turkey, and eggs\nseafood — salmon, sardines and tuna\norgan meats — liver, kidney and pate\n\nPlant foods containing non-haem iron can give you iron too. If you follow a plant-based diet, you will need to eat about 80% more iron to meet your dietary requirements.</string>
    <string name="iron_benefits">red blood cell function\nhelps move oxygen around the body</string>
    <string name="iron_sources">red meats including beef, lamb, kangaroo\nfish\npoultry\nwholegrain cereals\nbeans — kidney beans, edamame beans and chickpeas\nfortified breakfast cereals\ndried fruit</string>

    <string name="spinach_description">Spinach</string>
    <string name="magnesium_name">Magnesium</string>
    <string name="magnesium_symbol">Mg</string>
    <string name="magnesium_description">Magnesium is a mineral that is essential for healthy muscles, nerves, bones and blood sugar levels. If you don\'t get enough magnesium in your diet over a long time, you may be at a higher risk of health problems such as heart attack, stroke, diabetes or osteoporosis.\nMagnesium is needed for many processes in the body such as keeping muscles and nerves to work properly, keeping blood sugar and blood pressure at the right level, and making proteins, bone and DNA (genetic material)</string>
    <string name="magnesium_benefits">makes energy\nparathyroid gland function</string>
    <string name="magnesium_sources">legumes\npeas\nbeans\nnuts\nspinach\nwholemeal bread\nmilk</string>

    <string name="tomato_description">Tomato illustration</string>
    <string name="potassium_name">Potassium</string>
    <string name="potassium_symbol">K</string>
    <string name="potassium_description">Potassium is a mineral that is essential for all of the body\'s functions. It helps your nerves, muscles and heart to function well, and also helps move nutrients and waste around your body\'s cells.\n\nPotassium has many important functions:\nIt allows the nerves to respond to stimulation and muscles to contract (tighten), including those in the heart.\nIt reduces the effect of sodium (present in table salt) on blood pressure.\nIt helps move nutrients into cells, and waste products out of cells.\n\nYour kidneys control potassium levels in your body and get rid of excess potassium. If your kidneys do not work properly, potassium may build up in your blood. This can be a very dangerous condition, because it may cause your heart to beat irregularly or stop beating (cardiac arrest).</string>
    <string name="potassium_benefits">controls the balance of fluids in the body\nhelps your heart muscle work properly\ncontrol blood pressure\nprotect against strokes and cardiovascular disease\nprotect against osteoporosis\nprevent kidney stones</string>
    <string name="potassium_sources">leafy green vegetables\ntomatoes\ncucumbers\nzucchini\neggplant\npumpkin\nbananas\nbeef\nfish\npoultry\nnuts and seeds</string>

    <string name="zinc_name">Zinc</string>
    <string name="zinc_symbol">Zn</string>
    <string name="zinc_description">Zinc is an important mineral involved in various bodily functions – growth and development as well as immune function.\nZinc also helps to produce the active form of vitamin A and transports it around the body.\nZinc is naturally found in cells throughout the body. It helps the cells to grow and divide, and is necessary for the activity of enzymes, proteins, and DNA (your genes). The body cannot make zinc, so you need to get it from the food you eat. It is mainly stored in the muscle and bone.\n\nZinc is important for many of the body\'s functions:\n\nImmune system: The body needs zinc to fight off infection. People who don\'t have enough zinc in their body may be at greater risk of infections. Children and older people are at greater risk.\nWound healing: Zinc supports skin health. If you don\'t have enough zinc in your diet, it can lead to skin changes that can look like eczema at first. Zinc supplements may be used to help people who have burns or leg ulcers that heal very slowly or don\'t heal.\nTaste and smell: Zinc is very important for one of the enzymes you need so that you are able to taste and smell.\n\nHaving enough zinc is especially important during pregnancy, and for children to ensure they grow and develop properly.</string>
    <string name="zinc_sources">meat\nfish\nshellfish\npoultry\ncereals\ndairy foods\nbread\ncereals</string>
    <string name="zinc_benefits">\t\nwound healing\nmaking new cells and enzymes\nprocessing carbohydrate, fat and protein in food</string>

</resources>